Naomi Winchurch

Address: 55 Birchwood Road, Lichfield, Staffordshire, WS14 9UN

Mobile: 07922664525 E-mail: naomi@winchurch.co.uk Website: https://nwinch1512.github.io/13-react-portfolio/#/

Profile

Creative, and highly motivated with extensive experience in both the public and private sector. Organised, adaptable, a great problem solver, keen learner, works well alone or in a team. Background in analysis and data visualisation, recently completed University of Birmingham Front-end Web Development bootcamp. Portfolio of web development projects. Excited to continue working in new web development.

Key Skills

- **JavaScript**
- GitHub
- **HTML**
- Node JS
- Advanced Excel. PowerPoint and Word
- Quantitative analysis, data visualisation
- React
- **Bootstrap**
- CSS
- Project management
- Oral and written communication •
- **JQuery**
- Agile
- Figma
- Geospatial mapping
 - Team working

Achievements

- Consistently performed bootcamp weekly assignments to a high standard gaining an A grade overall.
- Performance award for excellent project management of Olympics and Euro 2012 multinational research projects.
- Received company award for innovative use of InstantAtlas to visualise data. The Guardian website showcased this work as being one of the top 10 government data visualisations in the country.
- Enabled WMRO to gain quality accreditation by participating in its continuous improvement programme.
- Achieved passion for customers' award at Masterlease for producing high quality written work.
- Won John Westergaard award for attaining the highest mark for my research dissertation at University.

Work History

Oct 2014 - current: **Iterative IT**, Company Director

Lichfield

- Completed web development bootcamp which covered: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React, JQuery, Moment JS, Jest testing, ES6 and Node JS.
- Completed series of individual and team web development projects following agile methodology.
- Final team project utilises Spotify API to add value to users experience by offering music recommendations based on users' combined music history.
- First team project utilised Spoonacular API to make recipe recommendations based on specific dietary or allergy requirements.
- Company secretary responsibilities.
- Assisting in day-to-day management of company.
- Liaising with accountant to ensure accounting records are accurate.
- Contract management.
- General business administration duties.

Mar 2013-Oct 2014: Maternity leave/ career break.

Feb 2011-Mar 2013: TNS Global Market Research, Consultant

London

2012-2013

- Managed and implemented multinational online sports sponsorship research projects (budget £330k) on behalf of McDonald's Europe and McDonald's Global.
- Analysed findings of sports projects (including use of regression analysis, factor analysis and statistical significance testing) to make recommendations over direction of McDonald's sports sponsorship.

Naomi Winchurch

Address: 55 Birchwood Road, Lichfield, Staffordshire, WS14 9UN Mobile: 07922664525 E-mail: naomi@winchurch.co.uk

Mobile: 07922664525 E-mail: naomi@winchurch.co.uk Website: https://nwinch1512.github.io/13-react-portfolio/#/

 Wrote annual deep dive reports on McDonald's key markets based on analysis of online survey data, whilst taking into account business priorities and market context.

- Liaised with clients across McDonald's Europe to gather their requirements and undertake analysis in response to their business needs.
- Contributing to management and reporting of McDonald's monthly tracker in 32 different countries
- Redeveloped quarterly family measures and monthly scorecard reports in line with McDonald's changing requirements (including automation of many elements using advanced Excel). Trained and supported staff on running the reports.

2011-2012

- Secondment to British American Tobacco to work on Global Marketing, Strategy and Insights Team at their Global headquarters. Analysed data, from several sources, to produce strategic market overviews on BAT's top 40 markets, on behalf of the CEO. These assessed BAT's performance and the market context to identify strengths, weaknesses, threats and opportunities for BAT across the globe.
- Provided business intelligence (using Business Objects) to Senior Marketing professionals across the globe in response to business needs.
- Undertook innovation and competitor reviews to benchmark BAT's performance, to help meet the priorities of the business marketing strategy.
- Represented TNS at key BAT business meetings and events.
- Kept abreast of changes in tobacco regulation, and product innovation.

Jan 2007-Oct 2010: Marketing Birmingham (formerly WMRO)

Birmingham

June 2010-Oct 2010 (Policy Advisor secondment)

- Undertook economic analysis into labour supply and demand, culminating in 30 Local Authority profiles which influenced public sector skills priorities in the West Midlands, subsequently presented findings to public sector decision-makers.
- Wrote a research paper for Business Link and other public sector partners into how West Midlands Higher Education Institutions contributed over 1.6 billion to the economy.
- Mapped the community resilience index to show policy-makers which communities were most vulnerable to shocks in the economy geospatially.
- Responded to ad-hoc information requests from internal and external policy-makers on a daily basis to share knowledge and improve policy-making.

Jan 2007-June 2010 (Research Executive)

Birmingham

- Analysed quantitative secondary data in Excel to quantify and monitor policy issues identified in the Regional Economic Strategy to help close the West Midlands' £15 billion output gap.
- Played instrumental role in developing web-based research enquiries service by representing user needs and testing the service. Managed the online and telephone research enquiries service - handling approximately 40 external research enquiries each month. Customer satisfaction with the service (average score of 3.7 out of 4) exceeded the KPI target.
- Kept up-to-date with over 40 data sources to update the State of the Region datasets and became a 'go to' source of data knowledge for other researchers and policy makers across the West Midlands.
- Used data knowledge to develop indicators to include in monitoring frameworks to track the West Midlands' progress in tackling a range of policy issues.
- Evaluated quantitative survey data in SPSS produce research insights into e-business adoption.
- Wrote over 20 research reports in Word to present research findings and identify policy implications for policy-makers.

Naomi Winchurch

Address: 55 Birchwood Road, Lichfield, Staffordshire, WS14 9UN Mobile: 07922664525 E-mail: naomi@winchurch.co.uk

Mobile: 07922664525 E-mail: naomi@winchurch.co.uk Website: https://nwinch1512.github.io/13-react-portfolio/#/

• Managed several research projects worth up to £10k, which received high customer satisfaction scores.

June 2005-Jan 2007: **ECOTEC Research and Consulting Ltd**, Research Assistant Birmingham

- Undertook qualitative data analysis to inform several national level social policy research projects worth up to £200k.
- Undertook evaluations of voluntary and community sector projects and bid appraisals.
- Carried out fieldwork and desk research.
- Exceeded individual contract value target by delivering £65k of contract work.

February 2004-June 2005: **Masterlease (UK) Ltd**, Senior Administrator

Birmingham

- Sourced information for tender responses and proposals and contributed information to 'Knowledge Bank' a web-based system set up to share information across the company.
- Monitored the success rate of proposals and tenders using bid to win ratio and producing reports on sales performance against targets, for management to help prioritise which tenders we completed.

July 2003-February 2004: **Temporary Agencies**, Administrative positions Birmingham

Education

2022 – 2023:	The University of Birmingham Skills Bootcamp in Front-end Web Development (grade A)
2000 – 2003:	The University of Sheffield Degree: BA (Hons) Sociology 2.i
1998 – 2000:	Shrewsbury Sixth Form College A-levels: Sociology, Art, English Language (22 UCAS points)
1993 – 1998:	Harlescott Secondary School, Shrewsbury GCSES: nine grade A/A*, one grade B (including English, Maths and Science)
Training	

- The Javascript Course 2022, Udemy
- Google BigQuery using SQL, Udemy
- Microsoft Power BI, edx
- Market Research Society Advanced Certificate in Market and Social Research (distinction)
- PRINCE2 practitioner
- Effective report writing (Emphasis)
- Introduction to statistical analysis using SPSS (fast track) (SPSS)
- Presenting data master class (Association of Regional Observatories)
- Presentation Skills (TDP Sheffield UK)
- Advanced writing skills (The Plain Language Commission)
- Project management (ECOTEC Research and Consulting)
- Microsoft advanced Excel and intermediate Word, PowerPoint, Outlook (Masterlease UK Ltd)

Interests

I enjoy reading, weightlifting, jogging, cooking and spending time outdoors with my family.

References available on request.